So
we are in the
middle of our third meditation which
who can say first days
be healthy second
ramza for that you take
I want to repeat to you again you can
repeat to do And of the 6 meditations What
we are going to do today some may
not work for you
will not work only Self-care
and you will be able to understand this in your young
teenage years or later because
never
meditation
works If you will only
focus attention on yourself third
third step is that you
remember those beautiful things when you are
right when you remember that you were
different and yourself my teacher told me that
you need to take into account what you
need about all living beings because and
you are one of them so don't think that you
are not on this list so no no no it doesn't
work Because everyone has the same
access and the same rights and you also
have
Buddhist
how to call it you know the Buddha himself
in self-Buddhist orientation this is not
Buddhism is what you know it is not even the
idea that when you want to do
good to someone on  Self-harm doesn't work that way either.
So you have to
worry about yourself and others in the same way. I
have good friends who are
Buddhists who are involved in
helping others but don't worry about
themselves and that's why they
know that's why they get sick or something
happens to them. I'll emphasize again
that you need to be healthy
and take care of yourself otherwise you won't
be able to continue.
So we're going to move on with this text. Are you
ready?
I like
going through Tibetan.
You can of course go through it. And I'm
just planting seeds for you for next time.
You don't need to focus now on
learning this language. Girls. Where does it
mean that
this single line
Kyoto. I don't know. We're the ones in this
concept. You know, we were
involved in what the
story in Kyoto about the king told. And let's
turn to the photo. Maybe this is
my brother. By the way, he's 72 years old.
[Music]
in Montana, the states are being edited. They're just
involved in harvesting wood
for poor people and you know, this is what
we're doing.  We call great people when
they do great things. And you know,
those people who really think about others
and this is a
beautiful picture of what they are and what
they really do, because
look, he includes his body and he
makes a presentation that is really important
because he actually puts 50% of
his body into the process itself and the story
of this king, what he asked to be given, to give
his body, I repeat again,
50/50% of his body, he wanted to give it
to people and we just talked
about it in Kyoto because he has the highest
motivation to share even his body
50/50 with people, his body was constantly
recovering and he was physically feeling
very good all the time and feeling better and better.
We actually stopped at Lamrivia for now,
one line went by,
actually driving Tim crazy because
we actually got a little bit behind, but
this story was so beautiful
because
I wanted to stop there and you
can read it again if
you like it and it was actually very
relevant to our meeting in Kyoto. We did
things chose this city Kyoto But that and not
Tokyo because the
Tom dynasty was founded in China
1400 years ago and in fact thanks
to these dynasties in Central
China
Buddhism continued to develop and that is why
Kyoto is one of the content that continues the
dynasty subtle it will sound strange
but it is more Chinese than other
Chinese cities unlike all
other Japanese cities because there is a huge
community of
Chinese
China experts And of course there is If you have the
opportunity to join the programs in Kyoto
please do it It is
just an incredibly beautiful place and the
people are very warm and kind We were
there if you remember two weeks ago
when there was cherry blossoms and all the people
from 20 to 50 years old were in the cinema and in
kimono I don't know what the correct cinema
is called for men but
it was so beautiful see it and
be in this place that
honors
cherry blossoms as well as the big
World Cup For example in football
in America Or in Europe and all
all
you know all people are born in the same way
in this it's like in America again I say like
football We are happy or in Europe
in the same way there are a huge number of programs
that you can join from
short-term and long-term
programs so
we have completed this line in
Tibetan and we will ask Dima again to
go to this line again in the sutra And
what does this mean he is addressing those
people who do similar
good deeds as for the benefit of other people he
says This with joy and this is just like this
This is the third part that we will now
look at Once we go through it we
can move on to that step what does
the practice of exchanging yourself
for others actually mean the
first line means about the bodhisattva it is
about the bodhisanctura
sculpture - this is natural you know such a
light The radiance which is the hair yes Which they
cut and go as an offering to others and
here is this you know
this Beautiful Pearl which means the mind
which is in your skull this is what it
means when they do this presentation
this line about history and in fact which is
very connected to the beginning here the birth of the
course shine I think  that was in
1991 or 92 when it was in
new york and some of the kadyu tradition kakyu
other tradition than son kapa they
asked
you know they were somewhere around 20 15 I
apologize to the people and they wanted to learn the
Tibetan language because they wanted to
go to a retreat well and of course go to a
long term naratrit and there read
the prayer of the Turkish language and I thought about
you how much is this another tradition they had to
pass on part of the court 3 or the scholars
about the court 3 and I thought God how cool it
was and I
read the
sutra of the golden light to them It's just you know
like the national book of Mongolia and there is a
story about so wandering So we means the
tigress of the stem language lyojen
means to pass or give your body and
this story about the beautiful beautiful
ringtone Chip and this is magasatva in
Sanskrit he was magasat ra but his
name was gay magosatkova meaning
great effort great gentlemen That's how it
translates and he  was there in the forest that
he saw that a
tigress she was dying because she was
sick and she had four
tiger cubs that she was supposed to feed her
milk but she had no milk anymore
because she was dying from lack of
strength
and as it is transmitted This story is in the
lamrim and he said
this is a bullet dream eve means
because she was in despair because she she
was on the verge what does
on the verge mean I honestly have never
seen it written in other texts
And she that is the tigress was so
sensitive that she wanted could eat
anything so that the milk would not appear
and here this prince
decided to give his body and He lay down
next to her
and he simply told her
Eat me And she could not because she had no
strength
and he What he did he broke off a branch
he broke his
chest with this branch with a
splinter and lay down next to her again And in this
way he gave his body and since he was
already dying he said let's
agree here's what if  you are
my body now
when I become a builder you must be become
my first disciple become a follower And
of course at that time he died
She of course
filled with strength passed the milk to her
children and that's how the first 5 disciples appeared to be
in this world
his first five students the so-called
first That's
how you see the compinier what is
called in Tibetan
he didn't pass on to them the higher teachings he what
we call the higher truth and and
passed it on to them three times and they had
such a connection through the heart was
strong between them that it really became the
truth and he more
he stopped a little after that
to pass on the teachings and because he thought that the
higher teachings were very complex and not
understandable and others but then he resumed
this practice Believe me when you yourself will
delve more and more into all the
teachings the
outside world will seem to tell you that
no we don't understand you just like
lordbuda he waited he wasn't
sure how this teaching would be perceived
perceived by other people I think
he completed and did  a pause for a
few weeks
before he then began to transmit the
teachings further here is the story against Greece
I don't know
These students we will call them that because we
went through the court of golden light we
took them through the chapter where
this story was mentioned and just then in the 90s I
transmitted this story and
then I said that I wanted to
transmit And the teachings about the meditation of emptiness
but at that time at that time I was studying other
traditions in the tradition sleep drips and so I
decided that I
thought to ask the teacher if it is good
when you move to another tradition
And I said that I can't
tell everyone all the time about the story of the tigress
I want to go further and just their lama
in response to this request To be honest I
answered that that is exactly it and for me it was a
traumatic experience because some of
my students she somehow left because that's how
we started Sia when there were
left and the other part 50% of all the
first students it's 6-7 people and that's how we
started the training aci so if you are
interested in the sutra of the golden
radiance please  you can read it all
further we will now continue this
text
this is a famous person who gave his
hair to someone else
horn means Keram and it means
Ja taka that is the story of jatika
birth Da that is the previous life will be
yepa suma means our Lama for this 24
day day 24 day practice of learning
he and here it is actually described about how
he passed on this
mastery for 24 days
next paragraph
it means
Our teacher Lord Budva great mahogruna
great compassion That's how he really is Here it is
told how he became bud just like
the story of the king in
Kyoto how he became then
in the future he became what we
call please
next means our heaven
tell ran your mats
sam hyu nepa
rana means ourselves or we ourselves your
means only we exclusively we ourselves bass
that means nothing else Sandy we
focus on what we want rantseva
that is for people who only focus on
what they want these things will be
called k that is difficult
If you have the habit of
focusing exclusively on yourself
worry about it such things as handing over the
body to others will be them  right complicated
but there
is another line what is Milan Yango So you
can on our level As you go through
rutrit this week you can hear this
story about people
Listen I want to say by the way that this is not a
sacrifice but sharing your body I don't want
you to think that King Sri-sina
was giving his body to others and to a person this is not the
main point of view and this is not
and this is not why he went
why he was cut into pieces the
main motivation was that he
had the awareness that other people have
absolutely the same right to 50% of his
body and instead of
money or support he gave
gave his body that is the focus here on that
and other people have absolutely the
same right to your time on your money
or something else that is once again
the focus here on that he gave part
i.e. 50% of his body to other people because
he had the awareness that other
people have the same right to this 50% and just like
him for what is the
awareness after the retreat for me and
also rhetorical experiences when you come in
in erythroma completely different
start you know animals
behave differently and Ants enter differently here for
example I had such an interesting
observation of a butterfly in he so
you know to the side all the time moved and very
strange It all looked to me from the side
because you
know once again and here we are talking about
that Okay here this part I can give to
others this part you can give to yourself
So this line where you divide or
make a division it is very important
when it goes it stops this line
and what the teaching says I this if you
meditate this week you know there is no
other way How can you
cut your body in a normal or easy
way and do it but you can
pray
for the day
when you can do it And by the way
and there is such an
effort when you direct your intention to
be so concentrated in the future
if such a sadve
I will give the story of my teacher he was
somewhere around 50 and he is
My teacher passed it on to me when
And you know such a cohort of
young people is gathering he already packed all the things
he wanted to move across the
road we saw  What do you know in New
Jersey he mentions again New Jersey the state where the
forest appeared yes you
know between the big roads and he chose a
place to live you know such a
small house in the
forest far in the forest Believe me it took
three days to get there
and he went there for three days to live in the
forest and
when we came back from there one of the students
said listen it is very very difficult to
meditate in the forest itself the teacher says yes of
course
meditating is much better at home oh yes It is
really true I tried it Believe me
personally it is not always the right way
I tried the same meditation did
not work in my case so you know
start something moderate and do not
make people pay attention to you
because the practice
that you come here the practice of exchanging yourself
for others and sharing the practice of sharing with
someone is the main principle that no
one knows about it That is you
do it in an incredible way but
invisible So this week just
pray that you can
reach
that life or that opportunity and the understanding
that people have absolutely the same right
to your time  at your own expense just as
you and you will get used to the right of others just as you do to
your right
very gradually include this thought in your
practice And of course you need to include
the understanding of emptiness and if you see the
direction you have come to, you can
personally affect every living being
directly And in this world and in others
so don't try this practice before then
because it will go crazy on us
But there will come a time when you
can help any living being
directly And that's what we're working on
But first you need to see the
emptiness directly
if people tell you that Oh I don't want to
see the emptiness directly I just want to
study compassion Yes no that's what compassion is
by the way a very good conclusion you know
who you
know when there are such beautiful people with
such crowns on their heads yes And they
tell you something I do
n't know what it is on their heads but
how I don't know how it will lead us to
survive but let's continue here's a
picture of a tigress with her cubs just
think about it maybe sometime this
week when you  do your meditation there will
come a time when you will go deep into the
understanding of emptiness that you
will be able to help every
living being equally And you will have no limitations and
instead of driving yourself crazy
to
help only 10 people with your
limited body do it And this with another
way i.e. get a million bodies and
Help three people It is much easier
and more sustainable do not
try
and do not try to do something with a limited
body You will not be able to achieve the
same fact but just pray for
more i.e. the idea is that you
think about this story of the king and
if you do not have it or do not know how to
convey this to you because I translated
the whole story and we have it We have published it
Absolutely free of charge
Diamond caterprise edition
on the site you can find Diamond cater
Press or I apologize and on the
educational platform just Read and
share on and it will be absolutely this
will be absolutely enough and try
to be compassionate that other people have the
same right to something in this world
maybe this is such a radical interpretation
and that is what it is  As you heard that they
also have the same time and on your time
or right and return this thought all water that is let it
stay with you
because
in you it will in a way polish your
meditation and motivation What you do in
this world in Kyoto For example we
talked and did meditation you
know with businessmen we called it
mushroom meditation
And And this is a
reference to that
reference that mushrooms grow in
the dark actually and it is actually such
you know a refrain or a transference to that about other
other your life because they we
have a great darkness for example between other
worlds or between other lives of ours
and also it
this darkness can envelop us in
the future And now we have this light
that we have That's all life and but we
know at the same time that time it flows that is
this light time it flows it is
limited and
we need to understand this so that you can
effectively manage your
time Have the opportunity to speak and that to
help yourself in the same
way
first of all you understand that
if you have a choice of course  you can not
only help yourself but also others
because after that you will not have such a
choice i.e. between mushrooms in quotes or
between these spaces and times between
one darkness and another we do not know
where you will go next Yes Where you will end up and
here you are in this world we are not for
so long And and that is why you have a Great mission
and task to help everyone so
here we will once again go to the argument
which in this text puppy
means
And it makes sense to take care of
other people in order to
have this
beautiful warm good good
idea that we want to
take care of other people
He says that you know if you
think about it it
seems very logical
that you should take
care of others
and not only about yourself it is very
logical Well now again in the dialogues
why is it logical Berna means For
example
when you are
well How to say what does this field mean the
field where you grow crops Well for
example we were driving to Sangal and We were
driving through beautiful fields I'm
sorry We were driving through Here not far from the
fields near Phoenix  but
but people
this is like your field if you want to
grow something by the way for those who are here you
saw that they are clearing some land here they
are clearing it and I don't know why they are doing it
maybe they are doing something that they will
study something it seems to me that the land here
was bought out now near us and they
cleared me all
honestly they cleared all the trees all the
bushes and made you know such a sad
picture Olya I'm
going back to the text you need
such you know
beautiful beautiful soil Where will you
put your seed
For example we are preparing that spring for you
pointers or texts that will help you
and this is very for us
a little story because in order to
prepare it it
takes a lot of time and so think
of this practice as preparing the soil
Where you can then plant your seed
then he says I could give If I
could give my
[music]
diamond or diamond pearl
and here is actually a reference to the ritual when
you find a pearl or some such
precious stone And when you find
it in a river or in other water and then you
clear  and then you know
and then we'll say under the moonlight this
precious stone shines you know like in
Aladdin's lamp can then fulfill your
wish So who is this soil these are the people
who your practice and other people who
help you get everything you
want it's like that nurturing soil
and Pearl precious stone that you
can get if you practice
and nurture this soil
So let's move on to the text I'm going to
cut off a piece of your body for you now oh no no this is all just to make
you smile but the
idea is if you want something
but you need to rub your hands really well yes
because you need to worry about
other people and everything you want you
get and I personally can say that I
I couldn't achieve everything Yes but
most did I made an
effort to see in
every right practice that would help
my dream become like miracles financially
For a personal example and if you
can at least a little bit join
this idea of ​​equality of rights for everyone
and the idea that other people have the
same right to you including the
result  this thinking will be
incredible you know because it is very strange
now to accept very, very strange even
such a thought even to cry that
you will get joy from
cutting a part  hands or feet Yeah Well it's
not exactly funny I don't know how people
wish you happiness you know I think it's
sad but it's very interesting the
idea that other people and You have the
same rights to something and your life
will be just incredibly beautiful
and here's the Tibetan He says again
look
and not even in a spiritual sense not in a
spiritual sense or approach you can
get everything you want in your life
through others through working with others because
other people serve you the same way every
day for days everything you want You
can get because everything comes from
other people and you can't You can
just repay them by
doing for you and here's what he says in
Tibetan
and then the clothes that you're wearing this
green drink for example
that you're drinking right now and it may not be the
most delicious but the one you drank this
morning or right now like I
comes from other people
also interdependence
absolutely right He's talking about there's an
interdependence between there are other people
giving you everything you want and forget
about compassion forget
about that  that You don't need
to be selfish why Because you For
example had breakfast today because
you're wearing underwear For example Yes I
hope Yes
but who is it
Maybe someone you know needed to
fill up the tank because someone needed to
make an effort so that what
you're wearing Yes and so that it was on you
forget about other rights attention You already
owe these people
and because you owe even for the fact that you
had a chance to eat something This morning or
drink or wear clothes
You already owe someone
and because For example
all people of all people You have resistance as
their mothers and I didn't have to possibly
bring to my seventeenth birthday and
understand this text And you know
talk about it 20 years and invest
all your attention in it
in order to come to such a thought and
awareness
no seriously true
someone
in your life
spent their whole life all the time and all the money
that is they made a sacrifice of their life
For example a woman from gives her body
and gives her body
when she gives birth to you because you offer
For example women offer their body to
their children when they give birth
and you  happily you do it it's very very interesting
interesting approach because
you give
20 years of your life
growing up with these children and you give
your body in this way and here people
not only
people you know made such
offerings to you but any person did it
as a mother who gave and gave your
life in order to take care of you
my wife for example yesterday such an announcement
told me
what it was and now I remember you know Something
Something Oh I remembered I know someone who got pregnant again with a
fourth or fifth child I think
Yes
and my wife says listens Well she
must be this woman very happy I'm like that
she answers me and having children is the
most beautiful thing
and my wife has two children I'm like that
yes because it's the best thing you can
do in life and I'm like wow
and here
every person every person you
meet is like a mother who gave you
her life
and mother stepfather and here a little interesting
version of the translation So here ama
means mother
I tried to also conduct a parallel
Tibetan  classes three weeks I wanted to
transport him
to a one-year program of
teaching about the podsak we you because there
in my case you know
when I was still studying there were three wonderful
teachers who had to determine how much
Tibetan language allows me to pass the
exam and my
teacher me you just come to
our exams I'm like Well okay well
this is an oral exam I'm like sat in front of these
members
members of this examination committee He is a
very tall Lama one of them and each of
them is actually from those three people who were sitting there
and he I sat in front of him and they are all
three
I'm like Oh God Now something terrible will happen and
he is this Lama He tells me
Well here I'll ask you in Tibetan
tell me if you know I'm like Well okay Well
come on I don't know what will happen to me and he
tells me the word Ama
And I'm like
mom he's like class you're right
and he's like apa And I'm like I'm like dad
He's so great you came exam
Therefore this word for me personally it is
very important i.e. ama means mom
but here we have two moms yes Why
not your mom
means that they  were not your mother they are
here look in the text You have an
obligation
to worry about the happiness of another as well as
yours because they were your mothers an
infinite number and an infinite
number of times and what will I do and when
they were your mothers you
owe them you know
and I I continued
the words this beautiful word sanskrit
thyroid cancer means
not to worry about someone who has such a
need as you know like a child that needs to be fed clothed
clean for them
pay for their education
or something like a kitten
Believe that having a child and paying for
it everyone with him together is supreme and above And
this payment
and he tells you here in the text
these people were infinitely and an infinite
number of times mothers
but Believe that even if you have your
physiological mother everyone else Still
worry about you because you as proof of
that had breakfast today had food
on
think about it because you actually
owe them everything because you can
sit here now you continue to exist
you are something dressed you have something in you have something in
your stomach is located Yes and you owe
it to other people even think about it that
you owe it because he is full of other
people already in this life even
continue further
For example what is samba in
Tibetan
By the way you can buy it
on Amazon I don't know one of the oat companies
or you can buy a big bag
Yeah I'm sorry This is a bag that
is tied to the belt and
[music]
for in the Ancient tradition it meant that
You know
the monks had only two spoons of
something that is what happened that is when
you were studying you had this whole breakfast in your bag
if
you had a
spoon with you Yes you could in three minutes
when you had Maybe still time to wash your
hands before that eat your breakfast or
any food well this way it
happened this ancient times so he
mentions here this bag with
[music]
other some kind of grain crops which
were like oats for example or other grain
and by the way you can
use grains in that smoothie
uses prepare how it is done My
wife for example So anything so that you
despite  what you had for
breakfast today think about the fact that someone
planted the grain so that you could get it
and
just think logically how hard it is to
grow the grain to support and
then
feed you with bread I saw a
lot of farmland around us and
it's very hard work and work
think that someone grew this bread for
you this food it's very hard work
incredibly hard which helps you to be
resilient Yes that's why someone watered these
grain crops and it's also very hard In
short it's a very interesting word
because in India For example in a
village or in rural areas you
see people
running in front of your car and throwing
and throwing
grain at you and grain and when you drive by you
know you drive by a car that is in this
way you kind of insert these grains and
in fact they then clean them and eat them
so in ancient times Chukchak
meant
and they would start a cow and
make her go through the
grain with a shovel so that she would peel this
grain from the kernel from the grain itself from the
husk
We are from Sanskrit By the way from 25  dollars anu
tell me what it
means
like And we so
infinite life that is infinite which
cannot be measured And why does this word
appear here we have
people who
have invested
your labor so that you get food and
or wear clothes it is an incredible
number of efforters
so someone in English something someone put in a
huge amount of effort so that
you have these clothes and This is an incredible
amount of labor by a group of labor and Some of
these people will die dies And but
these some people just get it pennies
less than a dollar and you get these clothes
from these people
And it seems to me that here everyone who all of us are
dressed
never undressed
we had to
think about what
the sumaitri does And you know I think there was
once when We dressed the masters
such a beautiful suit Yes Well
maybe we will do it again So I
go back to the text So someone
takes care of you getting
these clothes you already
you already know
this is an obligation and are
obliged to your body
receiving help from other people Why because
other people took care  about
giving and giving you food and clothing yes
you have already received an investment your body
yes If you can paraphrase
for you is Here is this Beautiful picture
a Wait let's find another
paragraph sugenx seems your part
no
line palazzota
what does it mean
if two eyes well let's move on
[music]
where you are sitting now at this moment now
If it doesn't matter Is it some place
room castle
where is it what is it
short form and long it is kindness of
other people kindness
By the way the book
before that Catherine it is actually in
Ukrainian published book about
Eugenia you can also download it
now Catherine
came out in Russian and Ukrainian
we now
The Book of Introductions is in
Ukrainian for from one dollar
one dollar and 99 cents you can
get if you speak Ukrainian
If you are good roads it will give you anyway
someone
the place where you are sitting
and it means that a lot of people
beings many years ago took care
of you
someone laid a stone someone
built the walls someone For example
designed the walls
planted a tree  someone went and
mixed the cement mortar,
it's not only about the clothes here, not only the
breakfast you had this
morning, but also the place where you are,
if you're sitting here,
you owe it to yourself to be here.
And this is the house where you are, you
know, this castle, this temple was
built
a few hundred years ago, I don't remember
how old it was, one woman, I
think she was 74 or 75 years old, and you know,
[music]
she was laying the stones, and in fact,
this, for example, even this erythrocyte
center was built by someone, and people
did it with their own hands, most of them,
if you see it, go to the village here,
see the people who worked hard to
build even a medium-sized center
where you
can
have a house. By the way, and
they helped us with that, some people,
even volunteers, to build this
house.
And this is incredible, and believe me, it's very hard
work. I, for example,
helped my dad, someone, for
example, for me, he did it, like in my
case, opening a cafe is very hard and
dangerous work, even and again.  I say this
very difficult
and then we go back to the text
son
what does this mean not for a Buddhist
monk This is it
I think it was some kind of sleeping
bag
it was warm long long piece of
cloth of some kind That which they carried with them
and you could wrap yourself with it and
that way you were warm and now for
example it has become part of the
ceremony yes When you cover your
body in the monastery there is
even a person who can
give you sticks on the back if you are not
wrapped in this This is this cloth
that every monk nun has this
silk That is if you know you have different
varieties of them because in fact it
had to be
you had these easy to make them from wool
light wool than from cotton because there were a
lot of sheep that gave this
wool Velo means wool in short so
here in the text it means that Someone had to
take this wool off the
sheep and clean it prepare it and
make a beautiful art form from it yes that is
cloth
it means a carrier means to be
ready
this Chok means to be ready for what
to be ready to bring as  in this case
why is
he talking about your clothes
because you already owe another person or
people for even the smallest detail of the
fabric is on your body
for now any of you because it was
necessary for this it took a lot of
time to
prepare the fabric to make and clean
it well and then designs and beautiful appearance
and here now we will do a little
meditation I wanted you to
practice today And we already have one We have already
done a meditation on the same on the so-
called sameness exercises for everyone
That is we talked about what we thought with
whom we had a relationship the other week
what they wanted when they talked to you what
you wanted and whether you when you communicated
differences But could you ever
communicate with people could respect
their right to something in this case
equally of course the
question arises completely logically do other people have the
same right to you on your time what
we talked about today Veronica You can
spend your time sit you want just as it is is
it good This is one of the questions Yes
but now we will go further  deeper or other
people already have a
right to your time because you ate
this morning somewhere in some
room Maybe you have more rights
to you than you think that's what the
first meditation is about Can
you In this way look at
other people that other people have a right to us
Maybe even the same right to
be
Now we're going to do another meditation
this meditation that we do in DC
for example
release and we call it the croissant
meditation
it's just choose some thing some your
room Well I don't know For example
If you have a toast in front of you because a
green drink or fruit with you
and fruit For example Which ones on your table it
takes a lot of time and effort to get this
fruit on your wall
think about something What did I eat today and we'll
do Even such steps back Yes That's how
this food ended up on your
plate who
cooked who bought the products Who
delivered these products to the store or was
involved in what for example
planted a tree
it was Look at how people
work hard in on farmland
that is  Take any one product
some fruit or some food products and we'll
just do you know how to trace back
that is we'll trace the whole way how this
product got to your table we'll go then next there
's another meditation that Dying
I'm very beautiful and
this is a meditation of the
references back this is the first first step
and this is the so-called you know this as meditation
on the physical object And another
second
aspect and meditation helps with that
[music]
and this is just some you know
ideas that you can think of but again I
say let's focus on that
the first part of the meditation or the first type of
meditation We'll think about that you'll
take some products and trace
part of the product yes and the second
idea Take in that were you
think about the seeds that these
people needed not in order for her to plant this
tree and then you got this fruit and
so you have If you
count correctly and look at this picture there will be somewhere
50 thousand years of work
tracked all the generations or that
helped you get this  product
on the table now
But someone started 50 for example to
thousands of years ago and thousands of people
worked
a lot of years ago so that
now in this life you get this
fruit for example
that is since the same time people have taken care
of grains and so that they
sow the fields with these grains so that
in this life you get beautiful
bread For example
I have one and a half people in my cafe but
but of course We will think about what
100 sows of papers that these people have
poor people to prepare in order to
track what financial transactions
are taking place and so think about how much
time it took for this Okay
How much time do we have is that By the way for
this meditation about 10 minutes
So we start our meditation
tracking
and celebration of gratitude
were in one of the products so this
meditation has two medicines
Let's do 20 experiments
[music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [music] [
music]
[music]
your mind now
list opinion
bigger institution has form on happiness If
we respect
we teenagers in equal rights
others It is true that all of us
odnokovom
its time helping them
stop
[music]
where this idea
came from why I hear this where does it come from
him
Maybe I heard it here on a dream we had
this thought
I would like to feel This course of one
wanted to delve more into understanding
this idea
or you think that
let that wanted Me personally and
improve my life so that today the
feeling of dreams heard myself language will
I where it came from maybe it was then
when I was jumped for the first time started awakened
sounding on facial language
what was before before that I maybe so
thought to study in school
but delve into or not And where does this
thought and around all hair
this idea together because they discussed
this with you
in
high school history as a subject or
[music]
no Maybe something you there did not succeed
something could have fallen physically But
maybe you were interested in some to
some subject
[music]
I remember even the
first day of the mainland And how I before even when
I thought about school and I remember what it was like
in the family field I was very little
[music]
[applause]
I remember
[music]
I feel the quality of the fabric what it is
spring walked to two meditations for
the first time
[music]
some object which is the
evening of some object in your space and
as they say trace the line back
and last time from where And from where did this
fruit or product or clothes come to you and
thank them and find a
new reason to think And
thank the new It's very good you know
such an exercise thank everyone and the second the second
meditation that we did today and
[music]
By the way the second meditation it goes you
know especially in retrikas different times